

CONTACT INFORMATION

+421951776354
Telegram
mariiacherkashyna7@gmail.com
Linkedin
GitHub
Trnava,Slovakia

TECH SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- · React/Redux/Redux-toolkit
- Next.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Plasmo
- REST API

SOFT SKILLS

- Calm
- Inquisitive
- · Willingness to learn
- Ability to work efficiently both individually and in a team

LANGUAGES

- English Intermediate
- Slovak Upper-Intermediate
- Ukrainian Native

MARIIA CHERKASHYNA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am a Front-End Developer with hands-on experience specializing in React and Next.js. I excel at quickly learning new technologies and solving problems independently through documentation review and research.I am experienced in debugging, maintaining existing codebases, and contributing to the development of new features.

My commitment and adaptability make me a promising addition to any collaborative environment.

Discover more about my professional background and explore my work on my *portfolio page*.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Cinemania, Link [HTML, CSS, JS, Parcel, REST API]

A responsive website featuring the latest popular movies of the day, week, and upcoming month. The design includes a mobile-friendly menu, dynamic daily movie ratings, a diverse film library, and modal windows for trailers and detailed information.

Role: Developer.

<u>MONEY GUARD</u>, <u>Link</u> [HTML, CSS, JS, React, Redux-toolkit, REST API] Instrument for analyzing your financial state, optimizing finances, and effectively managing them.

Role: Scrum-master, developer.

<u>Water Tracker</u>, <u>Link</u> [HTML, CSS, JS, React, Redux-toolkit, REST API, Node.js]

An aplication where you can monitor the amount of water consumed. Role: Scrum-master, developer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Leo•Source | Feb 2024 - Present

- Developing and maintaining user interfaces using UI libraries, TypeScript, React, Next.js and Plasmo.
- Integrating the client side of the application with REST APIs, handling different request states.
- Collaborating with backend developers to synchronize work on the project, with some involvement in backend development.
- Implementing responsive and mobile-friendly interfaces to ensure proper display and usability on various devices.

Team Leader

Novares Company, Slovakia | Feb 2022 - May 2023

- Led a team of operators in a manufacturing environment, overseeing production processes and ensuring product quality.
- Managed documentation processes, ensuring accurate and timely records for production activities.

EDUCATION

College of the National Pharmaceutical University in Kharkiv

2016-2019

Bachelor's degree of Pharmacy